A Guide to the Papers of Charles Henry Webb, 1867-1903
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Charles Henry Webb, 1867-1903
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8550
This collection consists of 14 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library on March 10, 1967.
Scope and Content Information
Webb discusses the publication, circulation and printing of a friend's book of poetry; recommends certain magazines and newspapers for its submission; comments on the proper payment due for a poem; recognizes public disinterest in poetry; sends apologies for a broken engagement; seeks to purchase a present; sends an autograph; assures an acquaintance of review of his poems; meditates on what is literature; and makes general comments about writing poetry and being a poet.
The correspondents include Theo[dore] Barber, Lizzie Dickinson, John Williamson Palmer, Henry Paret, Willy Waiter and Charles W. Stoddard.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Charles Henry Webb to Charles Warren Stoddard 1867 Mar 19, 4 pages, ALS
  Acknowledges news of Stoddard's book publication and requests a copy; says "must publish or die"; publishes a volume of Mark Twain's humors; calls Galaxy idiots for accepting Ina Coolbrith's poetry while rejecting theirs; suggests the Atlantic. Mentions [R. H.] Stoddard.
- Charles Henry Webb to Charles Warren Stoddard 1867 Aug 27, 3 pages, ALS
  Explains delay in answering letter; inquires about forthcoming book and offers to circulate it; inquires of Bret Harte.
- Charles Henry Webb to Charles Warren Stoddard 1867 Oct 7, 4 pages, ALS
  Receives book and promises circulation to such papers as the Citizen; suggests sending copies to daily papers including the Roundtable, Nation, and Atlantic; comments on book's inconsistent printing; comments on poor printing in Bret Harte's new book. Mentions The Jumping Frog[ of Calaveras County].
- Charles Henry Webb to Charles Warren Stoddard 1867 Dec 14, 3 pages, ALS
  Advises sending poems to Harper's Weekly or Bazaar and to Putnam's Monthly; should demand from the Galaxy a $30 honorarium for "The Bedouin"; notes success of Ina Coolbrith, slow sales of Stoddard's book due to public's reluctance to buy poetry; describes the difficult life of a poet.
- Charles Henry Webb to Miss Booth [1867], 3 pages, ALS
  Writes an apology for a "promised pleasure"; he was obliged to attend opera with Jersey friends due to standing invitation.
- Charles Henry Webb to Mr. Cozzens 1885 Aug 2, 2 pages, ALS
  Requests information about purchasing a pin or bracelet for a nice little girl, 18 or 20 years old; will remit price if he finds it acceptable.
- Charles Henry Webb to Henry Paret 1893 Mar 22, 1 page, ALS
  Does not recall the appearance of "Revenge" in book, but has had enough to assure that when "the blow and shaft has left your hand... you may find it sheathed in your own [heart]."
- Charles Henry Webb to 1901 Feb 17, 1 page, ALS
  Promises a volume of lyrics and ballads of Dr. John Williamson Palmer; praises Palmer's charm and subtlety of touch in his translation of Jules Michelet's French to English.
- Charles Henry Webb to Theodore M. Barber 1903 Jul 29, 3 pages, ALS
  Unsure if enclosed verse was also sent to magazine; says the more he works on something, the less he like it; reproduces three lines of a poem; expresses thanks for praise of John Paul's Book.
- Charles Henry Webb to Lizzie Dickinson n.y., Apr 5, 1 page, ALS
  Sends autograph; jokes about another Charles H. Webb, now on trial for forgery
- Charles Henry Webb to J. W. P. n.y., Nov. 12, 2 pages, ALS
  States that he did review new book of Palmer's poems, but editor may have forgotten it, recalls another review of book, not as appreciative; sends a copy of his new book "With Lead and Line."
- Charles Henry Webb to Willy Waiter n.d., 4 pages, ALS
  Remarks on coincidence of receipt of letter and lunch conversation; says W. D. Howell maintains Helmet of Navarre is not literature; mediates on what is literature. Mentions Union Club and Bertha Runkle.
- Photograph n.d., Print
  Magazine photo of C. H. W. standing
- Miscellaneous 1867 Nov 2
  Photocopy of page from Harper's Baazar with poem "To Lillie."